Hi friends, welcome back to Birlas Paarvai. We have been
watching many videos about cars on our channel. We have also
seen many videos about car insurance. So now we have
started doing many two-wheeler reviews on our channel recently. There
are many two-wheeler users on our channel. Our subscribers are definitely
everyone who has a two-wheeler. So
this insurance is an important topic that they need. Such a
topic is that many people come and do not
renew the insurance for two-wheelers. No matter how they do it, they
only do it with a few third parties. What are the
risks in this? What are the types of
insurance? Let's
watch this video with a comparison. We have also joined this video.
Our Vijay
Pro has also joined us. We also
do our car consulting support. As you know,
Vijay comes and does our buying support for us.
So, this video is definitely an
informative video. There is a
high
chance that you will have a two-wheeler at your home. Don't skip the video. Watch it without skipping.
[Music]
First, if we come and take insurance for two-wheelers,
we can say that there are two major types.
One comes and
says comprehensive. The other comes and says third
party. This
comprehensive is what we call
our own insurance, that is, the
insurance we take for ourselves and our bikes.
This third party is what you
go and hit someone. It
may be a pedestrian on the road, or a bike at home.
Maybe the passenger has some damage,
then this third party
will cover him, but if that happens, his
bike or scooter will not be covered.
This third party only covers humans. According to the government's rules,
this third party
is mandatory. So,
you buy a new
scooter or bike, then the
dealer will come and give you a compulsory five-year
package and
insure you. In that five-
year package, only the first year is
comprehensive, which is included, and from the
second year onwards,
only the third party will be there. Then this
comprehensive is yours.
You have to renew it manually.
What kind of process is there and
how can we do everything?
That's what we are going to see now.  If you
come to renew your insurance and
ask if you can go to our direct dealer and renew it, then
there is no compulsion. You
can do it yourself online. It is
very simple to do it online.
Now there are options like doing it on
your mobile. You can renew your bike policy in almost one minute, even with one click.
You just have to
produce your KYC. That too
online. For example, we can
come to an online portal and do a
comparison and see
what benefits we get from the dealer and online.
Now we can compare and see. For example,
I have a Royal Enfield bike. I
bought it in 2023.
Now I am in 2024. Now
we have that comprehensive insurance that has expired.  There
is only a third party, if you
come and see that comprehensive, when we
bought the bike, the ID came and it
was 18 locks, now let's go for 1 lock, if you
see this 1 lock quote given to us by the dealer side, it is ₹3500, okay, you can check it
online, the
link to this online will come, it
will be in the description, open it and it will ask you first, it will
ask for the vehicle number of that vehicle, so if
you put that registration number,
you will get the view plans,
now we are just going to check one of our vehicles for a demo purpose, we
don't have the number,
then
you can do this yourself and actually compare it and
see
which registration RTO you have, that
registration number, and make year,
I will tell you.  Year
later, which brand, that is, the
vehicle brand, came to us,
Royal Enfield, what variant is it, that is, the
Classic? Now, for example,
I am taking the Classic. I am buying a
350 cc bike in an ash color.
Now, they
are showing me many plans. In these plans, if you take it by default, you will see that it is
only 70k. Okay, so, come and increase it and I want one and 15 lakhs. Now, I am setting 15 lakhs. I am setting it and looking at my plans. So, I am getting all the plans from just 800 to 1500.
Now, when I add on like that,
many people are coming to the bike and they are not
putting everything from bumper to bumper.
Even, they are coming and giving us a new vehicle, a first,
a third.  All the add-ons for five years are
very good.
So now I will come here and tell you about zero
depreciation or bumper to bumper.
Then personal accident cover is
very important. So if we
do this, the minimum for us is 1300
to maximum 2800. We have those
plans online in different brands.
We can compare them and see
what is the claim settlement rate percentage.
Which one
has the best settlement and the best plans?
We can compare and make the decision that we
want. So this is
our optional. So if we do our decision and
compare like this, the maximum is
only 2800, but the
price given to us by the dealer is 3500. So it is almost
a  Saving 700 is a good saving for
that bike, okay, same ID value,
same ID value, 15 locks, I think they are
offering up to 85% on this online,
okay, now
we have told you about these add-ons, so let's
see what these add-ons have, RSA, we
say something like that, bumper to
bumper, that is, the car itself
has a bumper, where is the bike's bumper,
you can think of this, they say
bumper to bumper,
no, zero depreciation, they say something like that,
then RT A
says that,
you have an add-on, so I think
we also get roadside assistance here, let's
see that, now roadside
assistance is very
important, it is normal that
many people buy these bikes now.  People have
started traveling a little, for
example, those who buy Royal Enfields and even more so those who
buy super bikes, all of them travel, so
all these people come with this RSI and
come with many insurance plans and
give it by default.
Even if you don't, you can add it as an add or add it. There
are many benefits to adding it.
You go for a long ride. For
example, you go to
Malibu or Pondicherry and you come to a
situation where the vehicle is stopped and there is
no fuel. The
car may have broken down
or the battery may have failed. At such times,
this RSI
comes and is very helpful to us.
Just call the toll free number and
say that you are at this location. Even over the phone, what is that?
Bald, they
come to help us and guide us and help us
start the car. For
example, I am
stuck in a bad location and I say that I do
n't have any fuel right now. Even if
you say that RSL actually covers a minimum of 2 l,
they will come and fill us and guide us. Okay, so that's the main thing. If our bike breaks down and we sit on it, but we can't stay in one place for a long time with our bike, then this RSI will come and use it well. They will come and tow it and pick it up and go. Similarly, in
this kind of emergency situation, there is
accommodation in our car, like in our car insurance, there is a taxi facility, so
this add-on  If you add everything,
you will get all these benefits. Actually, many riders
come and do all this. Okay, so they are
all sure. Now, many people
are riding a lot after buying a bike.
But they are
not doing the insurance properly. So, if we
have done all this properly,
we
can utilize these benefits. And even
now, those who buy Royal Enfields are saying that they have bought it.
Actually, they are saying that they have bought it.
But they want to
know all this. Some people do not know what the advantages of this RSI are and do not know what it is. So,
they are all sure. It is a
benefit.
We can say that if
we buy bikes, now mostly
fiber parts are coming.
You have seen all these fairings.  So if we
fall down a big hill,
it is definitely not at the level of breaking, its quality is there, so we
change it,
so it is a little expensive,
but if we do this bumper to bumper,
it will come to you and claim
zero cost and
even replace it for you. So
many people replace that B2, so
you can do it yourself, you can also say another R.
This minimum, those who buy more than 1000,
or those who buy a super bike, the
first 102 two
years, this article, you
can definitely add something to our blood time. We have
seen many people on this
page of my car, saying that if this bike gets stuck in water, it will not spread. It is not like
that. You can actually
claim that and
get a full refund. You
can use all that RTM addon.  Total loss is
total loss, so that's why
these expensive bikes, that is, now the
minimum for a bike is 1000, so if you buy 2 bikes,
you definitely have to put in all these things, okay,
personal accident cover, all these
riders definitely have to add personal accident cover,
even if there is a minor injury, definitely it will come and
you will get a good settlement
or a good claim amount, come and
we can actually use it, right,
next time we come to EVIL, we
will bring all the new modules, they say,
for example, our battery is the
thing that we are afraid of when we come to EVIL, if the
battery goes out,
we will have to put in almost half of the cost of our bike,
so
we will start with separate modules for this EVIL battery.  They say that in case the
battery in your bike
dies, then
you can claim and get it replaced under the battery insurance. But
now
you know how it is,
you may think that it is covered under the warranty. It is covered under the warranty. It is covered under the warranty. But if
you come and get a blood effect, it
breaks in an accident. If all
this comes and is replaced for you, then
you can definitely
claim under this type of insurance and get the
battery replaced.
I think you must have understood that now. I mean, can
we claim so many things under the insurance of a two-wheeler? Are there so many
add-ons?
Now, they say that it is a
two-wheeler and they do not take out insurance. It is not advisable
for us to take out an insurance at a critical
time. This insurance will definitely
come and give us a major  Helppe will come and
do it for us, so don't leave your two-wheeler without
renewing it.
Just because you
get caught by the police, don't drive a third party vehicle just for fun.
Please renew the insurance for your
cell phone and your bike. What is that? A
maximum of ₹2000-2500
gives you almost all the modules. So, we
hope that this video has given you full clarity. We hope that we will meet
you again in another video.
Until then, I bid
you farewell. Yours,
Birla Vijay Bhai.